# **Irwin Alejandro Rodriguez Ramirez**

hi@iarodriguez.com +52 55669 46649

# Software full stack developer

Cuauhtémoc, Mexico City, MX

Software developer with more than 6 years of experience using Angular, NodeJS, Python, and React to build web applications, REST APIs, and hybrid mobile applications with Ionic. Experience in software infrastructure and database design. Fast learner who loves learning new technologies and tools every day. Strong interpersonal skills and highly motivated to create and deliver the best products and solutions.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

**Wizeline** 2020 – 2023

## **Software Engineer**

Work in multiple projects for clients in the north America region, as developer and consultant, delivering solutions and improvements in the software and the workflow. Some of the projects I collaborated are:

- Google Apache Beam
- Grupo Salinas BAZ Súperapp
- American water resources Selling plan system

**Purpura** 2018 – 2020

## Senior Full Stack Developer

Lead developer in charge of create, develop, and maintenance of all the client projects and its architectures, create code guidelines for all teams and Manage task and lead daily meetings.

- Develop web apps with Angular 4+, VueJS and mobile apps with Ionic.
- Develop and design of APIs REST with NodeJS and Laravel.
- Machine Learning introduction curse instructor.
- Database design, with MongoDB and MySQL.

**Creatima** 2017 - 2018

### Web developer

Developer JR, in charge of maintain legacy systems with PHP and Yii framework and develop new platforms as SPAs, Maintenance and personalized layouts of web sites for each client.

- Database updates and custom reports.
- Develop web apps with Angular 2+and Laravel.
- User Interface and experience design.
- Develop websites with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.

## **EDUCATION**

## Instituto Politécnico Nacional, Escuela Superior de Ingeniería Mecánica y Eléctrica

Electronic and Communications Engineering

Software speciality.

#### **SKILLS**

Frameworks - Angular (Advanced), NodeJS (Advanced), MongoDB (Advanced), React, VueJS, Laravel, NodeJS/Express (Advanced).

Languages - JavaScript (Advanced), TypeScript (Advanced), Python, Java, HTML (Advanced), CSS (Advanced), PHP, SQL.

**Tools -** Firebase, NPM, API REST, Git, Docker, Webpack, AWS (Lambda, S3, EC2, API Gateway), CI/CD, SASS, Jasmine, Redis, Mocha, Jenkins, Sentry, Jira, SCRUM, Kanban.